Sudeep Basnet

sudbasnet.github.io

Address: **5277 W 82nd ST**

Bloomington, MN

Email: **sudbasnet10@gmail.com**

SUMMARY

Dedicated, career-oriented individual with 4.5 years of professional experience as a Software Engineer and Data Analyst. Graduated with a master's degree in Computer Science. Worked in Agile methodology and used technology such as Java, Oracle, Python and JavaScript on Windows and Unix platforms. Interested in Software Development and Data Science.

SKILLS

Programming: Python, R, Java, SQL, JavaScript, HTML/CSS

Other Technical: Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Database Development, Systems Administration (UNIX),

Oracle, Snowflake, GIT and SVN, JIRA

EXPERIENCE

Technical Consultant | Oct 2019 - Current

Logic Information Systems, Bloomington, MN

- Developed korn shell-script programs for data manipulation and application of business specific logic in Oracle's enterprise data warehouse.
- Designed Cloud Data Warehouse in *Snowflake* along with stored procedures in *JavaScript*, and automated data loading with *Python*.
- Debugged and resolved issues in reporting dashboards of using MicroStrategy Developer, MicroStrategy Architect and MicroStrategy Intelligence Server.

Graduate Research and Teaching Assistant | Jan 2017 - Aug 2019

University of Nebraska – Lincoln (UNL)

- Developed Agent-based simulation models to simulate and predict social unrest on a geographic and temporal scale, in *Repast Java*. (Github Link)
- Developed a scalable clustering algorithm using *Python* to perform unsupervised learning on GIS data, with performance gain up to 60% compared to state-of-art algorithms. Published and presented Research Paper.
- Data Mining, Data Analysis and Data Management using *Python*, *R* and *Java*, utilizing parallel computing on Nebraska's second-fastest High-Performance Computing servers.
- Development and management of *PHP* backed application, and Data Visualization using *HTML/CSS*, *KnockoutJS*, *Google Maps JavaScript API* and *MySQL* database. (<u>View</u>)

Software Engineer - Data Operations | July 2012 - Dec 2016

Cotiviti Nepal Pvt. Ltd. | Kathmandu, Nepal | (Subsidiary of COTIVITI HEALTHCARE, Waltham MA)

- Experienced in Software Development using Oracle 11g and Java on Windows and UNIX platforms, involved in Import, Analysis, Designing & Development, Testing and Production support phases.
- Data Analysis of US healthcare data (HIPAA protected medical data). Prepared Analytical Reports per client-requirements using OBIEE and BIP.
- Implemented Oracle PL/SQL procedures, functions, triggers and packages for data management and statistical report generation on US healthcare data.
- Developed ETL procedures, documented and validated complex business rules for data transformation. Prepared technical specification, reviewed code, and performed unit testing for client-specific change requests.
- Optimized multiple large clients by 60 70% in processing time using parallel processes, re-designing back-end jobs, performance tuning, normalization and query optimization.
- Led multiple teams of Software Engineers through different projects for 2 years. Responsible for Code Quality, Code Reviews, Design Reviews, Code documentation and Design documentation for maintainability.

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Computer Science (GPA: 3.8) | Jan 2017 - August 2019

<u>University of Nebraska – Lincoln, NE, USA</u>

Relevant Courses: Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Data Structures, Machine Learning, Systems Administration